<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">PMDMTarea02</string>
    <string name="about">About..</string>

    <!-- Menu Drawer-->
    <string name="settings">Configuration</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="logo_menu_drawer">Logo menu Drawer</string>

    <!--Settings-->
    <string name="choose_lang">Choose Language</string>
    <string name="switch_lang">Switch to English</string>


    <!--Personajes-->
    <string name="abilitiesTV">Abilities</string>
    <string name="descripcionTV">Description</string>
    <string name="mario_name">Mario Mario</string>
    <string name="description_mario">Mario (formerly known as Jumpman, and developed under the nickname Mr. Video) is Nintendo\'s mascot and the main protagonist of the Mario franchise. Mario made his first appearance as the protagonist of the arcade game Donkey Kong, released in 1981. \n\nSince Super Mario Bros., his abilities have included his jumping and stomping powers, which he uses to defeat most of his enemies, as well as his ability to gain powers from a plethora of items, such as the Super Mushroom, Fire Flower, and Super Star. \n\nThe games have generally portrayed Mario as a silent character without a distinct personality (Fortune Street is a notable exception). According to Nintendo\'s philosophy, this allows Mario to fit into many different genres and roles. \n\nIn most games, he is the hero who embarks on an adventure to save Princess Peach from his archenemy, Bowser, but he has also been shown engaging in many other activities besides adventuring, such as competing and playing sports with his younger twin brother and others.</string>
    <string name="abilities_mario">Mario\'s most notable ability is his Jump, which is his basic movement that he relies on to defeat enemies, avoid obstacles, and activate useful objects such as ? Blocks and P Switches. Although Luigi has superior jumps, Mario is more well-known. \n\nHe is also capable of performing several acrobatic maneuvers, such as the Long Jump, Backflip, Spin Jump, and Wall Jump, with the Wall Jump being one of his most recurring abilities. \n\nMario can also use a variety of basic martial arts attacks, including punches and kicks, although in most games, jumping remains his primary form of attack. \n\nMario\'s main weapon is the Hammer in Donkey Kong, although he often uses the Hammer as a weapon in Mario role-playing games (RPGs).</string>
    <string name="luigi_name">Luigi Mario</string>
    <string name="peach_name">Princesa Peach</string>
    <string name="yoshi_name">Yoshi</string>
    <string name="toad_name">Toad</string>
    <string name="warrio_name">Warrio</string>
    <string name="waluigi_name">Waluigi</string>
    <string name="description_luigi">Luigi is a cheerful, optimistic, kind, noble, relaxed, ambivert, sensitive, and dreamy character with a strong sense of justice and morality, just like his brother Mario. However, Luigi is also a bit more fearful and self-conscious, often becoming nervous when he senses danger.\n\nHis biggest fear is ghosts, but despite this, he is able to overcome his fears to save his friends. This bravery is most notably seen in the Luigi\'s Mansion series, where he faces ghosts head-on, even though he is visibly terrified.\n\nLuigi also displays a somewhat childish side, as seen in Mario y Luigi: Bowser\'s Inside Story, where he throws a tantrum when he fails to catch the worm causing them trouble or when he starts tickling the head stick.\n\nDespite his playful and sometimes timid nature, Luigi is fully capable of getting serious when necessary, showing great resolve and bravery when the situation demands it.</string>
    <string name="abilities_luigi">Pyrokinesis, Enhanced jumping abilities, Enhanced speed, Enhanced strength, Enhanced durability, Enhanced stamina, Enhanced agility, Electrokinesis, Negative energy, Master combatant, Indomitable will, Weapon expertise, Hammer proficiency, Leadership, Ghost hunting skills, Expert vehicle driver, Transformations</string>
    <string name="description_peach">Princess Peach is elegant, kind, intelligent, sociable, and adventurous. She has a warm heart and often acts generously, putting her friends, loved ones, and citizens ahead of herself. She tends to apologize excessively when she gets into trouble and requires Mario to rescue her.  Although she occasionally appears naive, she is generally sensible and shows more common sense than those around her. Examples include noticing a double in the background of the vacation guide video for Isle Delfino in Super Mario Sunshine, insisting that an emergency meeting continue even after Bowser briefly interrupted it, and deducing what Fawful was planning regarding her in Mario and Luigi: Bowser\'s Inside Story.</string>
    <string name="abilities_peach">Magic,   Enhanced speed,   Enhanced jump,   Enhanced agility,   Gliding,   Healing,   Telepathy,   Telekinesis,   Cooking skills,   Survival skills,   Dancing skills,   Leadership skills,   Umbrella proficiency,   Weapon experience,   Emotional empowerment,   Transformations</string>
    <string name="abilities_yoshi">Enhanced speed,  \nEnhanced strength,  \nEnhanced jump,  \nPrehensile tongue,  \nAbility to eat things and turn them into others,  \nEgg generation and projection,  \nFire breath,  \nTail whip,  \nLeadership,  \nTransformations</string>
    <string name="description_yoshi">He is a friendly and loyal dinosaur, known for his round body, large feet, and his distinctive green color, although Yoshis of other colors also exist. He has a large sticky tongue that he uses to catch enemies and consume objects, which often turn into eggs that he can then throw as projectiles.</string>
    <string name="description_toad">He is a resident of the Mushroom Kingdom and one of Princess Peach\'s most loyal assistants. His appearance is characterized by his short stature, a mushroom-shaped head (with red or other colored spots), a blue or yellow vest, white pants, and small shoes.</string>
    <string name="abilities_toad">Enhanced speed, Enhanced strength (when lifting objects in certain games), Agile and fast jump, Access to transformations through power-ups (Fire Flower, Super Star, Mega Mushroom, etc.), Ability to throw objects (like vegetables in Super Mario Bros. 2), High resilience and loyalty to the Mushroom Kingdom, Ability to drive vehicles in Mario Kart, Ability to participate in sports activities (tennis, golf, soccer, among others), Ability to navigate platforming levels with precision and speed, Role as an assistant and messenger in the Mushroom Kingdom,</string>
    <string name="description_waluigi">Known for being Luigi\'s eternal rival and Wario\'s companion. His name is a play on words combining \"Luigi\" and \"Warui\" (which means \"bad\" in Japanese). Waluigi is depicted as a tall, lanky man with long limbs and a cartoonish appearance. He wears a purple jumpsuit, a black shirt, white gloves, and a purple hat featuring an inverted \"Γ\" (similar to an upside-down \"L\") as his emblem.\n\nWaluigi is known for his arrogant, selfish, and often comical attitude. He is frequently portrayed as a cheater in sports games and competitions. Although he does not appear as a main villain in the core Super Mario games, he has played a recurring role in spin-offs such as Mario Kart, Mario Tennis, and Mario Party.</string>
    <string name="abilities_waluigi">Enhanced speed (especially in Mario Kart and sports games), Enhanced strength (notable in sports games like Mario Strikers and Mario Tennis), High and acrobatic jump (stands out in platform and sports games), Deception and trick techniques (in Mario Tennis and Mario Party), Ability to throw and hit objects (in sports and party games), Ability to perform special attacks (like the \"Dance Tornado\" in Mario Strikers and super strikes in Mario Tennis), Ability to participate in sports competitions (tennis, soccer, golf, baseball, among others), Access to transformations through power-ups (Fire Flower, Super Star, Mega Mushroom, etc.), Vehicle driving skills in Mario Kart, Physical endurance and agility in platforming and challenge games,</string>
    <string name="description_warrio">He is Mario\'s rival and evil counterpart. His name comes from the combination of \"Mario\" and \"Warui\" (which means \"bad\" in Japanese). Wario is short, stocky, and muscular, with an imposing and grotesque appearance. He is characterized by his large pink nose, pointed mustache, and mischievous laugh. His outfit includes a yellow cap with an inverted \"W\", a purple shirt, and purple or blue overalls, along with white gloves.\n\nUnlike Mario, Wario is greedy, selfish, and sarcastic. His main motivation is often the pursuit of treasures and riches, starring in his own game series called Wario Land and WarioWare. Although he often acts as an antagonist, he is not always portrayed as a villain in the main Super Mario saga.</string>
    <string name="abilities_warrio">Superhuman strength (able to lift, throw, and destroy heavy objects with ease), Striking and charging attacks (with his iconic \"Shoulder Charge,\" a move he uses to ram enemies and walls), Average speed (he is not very fast, but his strength compensates for his slowness), Jumping ability (his jump is short, but he can break blocks from below or crush enemies with force), Special transformations (thanks to special items in the Wario Land series, such as Zombie Wario, Vampire Wario, and Snowball Wario), Access to classic power-ups (Fire Flower, Super Star, Mega Mushroom, etc.), Gas attacks (in games like Super Smash Bros., where he uses his \"Wario Waft,\" a powerful gas attack), Ability to throw and strike heavy objects (notable in WarioWare and Mario Party), Participation in sports competitions (tennis, soccer, golf, baseball, among others), Ability to drive vehicles (in Mario Kart, where he drives heavier and more resistant karts), Enhanced endurance (due to his size and strength, he can withstand more damage than other characters),</string>

</resources>